<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-19T14:29:54-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/webtest/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Theodore Chiu</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Theodore Chiu</name></author><entry><title type="html">A Thousand Words</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/08/post4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Thousand Words" /><published>2017-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/08/post4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/08/post4.html">&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All images are owned and taken by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Theodore Chiu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/07.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_0081.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_0081.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_0084.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_0084.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_3871.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/IMG_3871.png&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/skylinebackground.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/skylinebackground.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/foothillspark.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/foothillspark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theodore Chiu</name></author><summary type="html">public static void main(String[] args) { if (args.length &amp;gt;= 1000) return true; else return false; } All images are owned and taken by Theodore Chiu</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Memories of the Homeland</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/07/Memories-of-the-homeland.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Memories of the Homeland" /><published>2017-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/07/Memories-of-the-homeland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/12/07/Memories-of-the-homeland.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;sfo--ind&quot;&gt;SFO → IND&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been at Purdue a couple months, and today was the first day of 20 degree weather. There are many things in Indiana which sharply contrast life in Cali. I’ve grown up in California all my life, and being out here in Indiana really puts into perspective my experience of home. The twisting mountains, flowing valleys and tropical Mediterranean climate are just a few of things I will never find in Indiana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/webtest/static/posts/foothillspark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Foothills Park in Los Altos Hills &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;topography&quot;&gt;Topography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact California’s unique geography affords it all three of these unique features. California has an abdunance of tall mountains cascading into deep valleys. This is a result of its location on a fault line. As the Earth’s crust folds into the mantle, tall mountains are formed. While one result of this is beauty beyond belief, it also results in the Achilles’ heal of California. Earthquakes. The shifting tectonic plates actively cause earthquakes. These earthquakes can cause extreme devastation as highlighted in Hollywood box office &lt;em&gt;San Andreas&lt;/em&gt; starring Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;geography&quot;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However one great feature of California is its climate. Situated on one of the Earth’s harmonic points dubbed mediterranean climate, California features dry summers and mild winters. In short, most of the planet has cold winters and hot summers. California, though, has a climate identical to coastal regions of the Mediterranean. This pleasant weather being one of California’s most attractive features. Consequently there are many crops that can be grown in California, that cannot be grown (well) in the rest of the United States. For example, grapes for wine are either grown in the Mediterranean, France, or California in the Napa Valley. All of these place share a similar if not identical climate, and California is the only place with this climate in the United States. The Achilles’ heel of this remarkable feature - is extremely dry summers responsible for yearly forest fires, which range in devastation from mild to severe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theodore Chiu</name></author><summary type="html">SFO → IND I’ve been at Purdue a couple months, and today was the first day of 20 degree weather. There are many things in Indiana which sharply contrast life in Cali. I’ve grown up in California all my life, and being out here in Indiana really puts into perspective my experience of home. The twisting mountains, flowing valleys and tropical Mediterranean climate are just a few of things I will never find in Indiana. Foothills Park in Los Altos Hills Topography In fact California’s unique geography affords it all three of these unique features. California has an abdunance of tall mountains cascading into deep valleys. This is a result of its location on a fault line. As the Earth’s crust folds into the mantle, tall mountains are formed. While one result of this is beauty beyond belief, it also results in the Achilles’ heal of California. Earthquakes. The shifting tectonic plates actively cause earthquakes. These earthquakes can cause extreme devastation as highlighted in Hollywood box office San Andreas starring Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson. Geography However one great feature of California is its climate. Situated on one of the Earth’s harmonic points dubbed mediterranean climate, California features dry summers and mild winters. In short, most of the planet has cold winters and hot summers. California, though, has a climate identical to coastal regions of the Mediterranean. This pleasant weather being one of California’s most attractive features. Consequently there are many crops that can be grown in California, that cannot be grown (well) in the rest of the United States. For example, grapes for wine are either grown in the Mediterranean, France, or California in the Napa Valley. All of these place share a similar if not identical climate, and California is the only place with this climate in the United States. The Achilles’ heel of this remarkable feature - is extremely dry summers responsible for yearly forest fires, which range in devastation from mild to severe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Servin’ it up</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/11/28/post2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Servin' it up" /><published>2017-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/11/28/post2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/11/28/post2.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;servers&quot;&gt;Servers!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed there is now an FTP tab! While this is mostly for my use since its password protected, it’s still something new on the site. I’ve always wanted to run a server, and since my network is a mess of cascading and parallel routers, the port forwarding and ip addresses were always difficult to manage. But, I finally sat down, diagrammed all the static ip’s and with some port forwarding figured out how to serve to the world wide web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dynamic-vs-static-ip-addresses&quot;&gt;Dynamic vs Static ip addresses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one caviat is that since I don’t own a domain name or a static ip, the server has to run a dynamic update client. For the people that don’t know how the internet works, each website is assigned an ip address, although you might not know it. For example no one looks up &lt;a href=&quot;http://31.13.69.228&quot;&gt;31.13.69.228&lt;/a&gt;, but that ip address belongs to facebook. In the same way people don’t go on typing strings of 4 numbers into their address bar when they want to go to a website, instead they type a domain name. Theoretically, typing the 4 strings of digits works for websites that own ip addresses. &lt;a href=&quot;http://31.13.69.228&quot;&gt;31.13.69.228&lt;/a&gt; belongs to facebook, since they bought it long ago. But for people like me who lack the funds to pay for a static ip address, but have internet, our internet service provider routinely changes my ip address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-workaround&quot;&gt;The workaround&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution is a dyanamic update client. The DUC routinely goes on the internet and checks its own ip address before uploading the information onto another server where I have registered for a subdomain (for free). This way whenver the ip address for my network changes, the server will discover the change and change the slave ip on the dynamic ip server, this in turn changes the subdomain to refer to that ip address instead of the expired one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-magic&quot;&gt;The magic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, not only can I access my files via sftp on my server from any computer with an internet connection, but I can also log in and manage the server via a command line interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future might hold VPN’s and even serve Apache… who knows?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theodore Chiu</name></author><category term="Tags" /><category term="Blog" /><category term="Post" /><category term="Tech" /><summary type="html">Servers! As you may have noticed there is now an FTP tab! While this is mostly for my use since its password protected, it’s still something new on the site. I’ve always wanted to run a server, and since my network is a mess of cascading and parallel routers, the port forwarding and ip addresses were always difficult to manage. But, I finally sat down, diagrammed all the static ip’s and with some port forwarding figured out how to serve to the world wide web! Dynamic vs Static ip addresses The one caviat is that since I don’t own a domain name or a static ip, the server has to run a dynamic update client. For the people that don’t know how the internet works, each website is assigned an ip address, although you might not know it. For example no one looks up 31.13.69.228, but that ip address belongs to facebook. In the same way people don’t go on typing strings of 4 numbers into their address bar when they want to go to a website, instead they type a domain name. Theoretically, typing the 4 strings of digits works for websites that own ip addresses. 31.13.69.228 belongs to facebook, since they bought it long ago. But for people like me who lack the funds to pay for a static ip address, but have internet, our internet service provider routinely changes my ip address. The workaround The solution is a dyanamic update client. The DUC routinely goes on the internet and checks its own ip address before uploading the information onto another server where I have registered for a subdomain (for free). This way whenver the ip address for my network changes, the server will discover the change and change the slave ip on the dynamic ip server, this in turn changes the subdomain to refer to that ip address instead of the expired one. The magic Now, not only can I access my files via sftp on my server from any computer with an internet connection, but I can also log in and manage the server via a command line interface. The future The future might hold VPN’s and even serve Apache… who knows?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A little about me…</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/09/08/post1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A little about me..." /><published>2017-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/09/08/post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/webtest/2017/09/08/post1.html">&lt;p&gt;As you might already know (from the title in your browser) my name is Theodore Chiu! I’m a programmer studying engineering at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.purdue.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Purdue University&lt;/a&gt;. I’m from Palo Alto, and I attended &lt;a href=&quot;http://shschools.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sacred Heart Prep&lt;/a&gt;, graduating in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been exposed to computers for most of my life, and I love programming! 
I first started programming in 7th grade when I checked out a book on Java from the library. Since then I’ve taken some classes,
watched some youtube videos, and checked out a ton more books to learn as much as a possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time I enjoy playing guitar, piano, and drums. &lt;a href=&quot;/webtestmusic.html&quot;&gt;Music&lt;/a&gt; is a large part of my life and 
I’m constantly looking for new songs to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Theodore Chiu</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Tags" /><category term="Blog" /><category term="Post" /><summary type="html">As you might already know (from the title in your browser) my name is Theodore Chiu! I’m a programmer studying engineering at Purdue University. I’m from Palo Alto, and I attended Sacred Heart Prep, graduating in 2017. I’ve been exposed to computers for most of my life, and I love programming! I first started programming in 7th grade when I checked out a book on Java from the library. Since then I’ve taken some classes, watched some youtube videos, and checked out a ton more books to learn as much as a possibly can. In my spare time I enjoy playing guitar, piano, and drums. Music is a large part of my life and I’m constantly looking for new songs to enjoy.</summary></entry></feed>